我很抱歉abc--Jeff
I'm Sorry.abc--Jeff
Zach这是最后一次调头回去了
Damn it, zach. This is theabclast time I'm turning around.
下次还是丢三落四的 你得自己负责
The next time you forget something,abcyou're gonna be on your own.
没球棍没法打球呀
I can't play without a stick.
那你就只好不打了
Then I guess you won't play.
不打就不打 反正打得糟透了
I don't care. I suck anyway.
别这么说
Don't say that.
我是全队最差的
I'm the worst guy on the whole team.
你不是
No, you're not.
那谁比我差?
Then who's worse?
你别管其他人 自己尽力就好
Don't worry about anyoneabcelse. Just do your best.
看吧? 你一个也说不上来
See? You can't name anyone.
Zach 别这样
Zach, stop it.
那你说呀
Then name someone.
说不上来吧?
You can't, can you?
Donny... Mark... Navid
Donny... mark... navid.
你真觉得我比他们强?
You really think I'mabcbetter than those guys?
当然
Yes.
快去拿你的球棍
Hurry up and get your stick.
Zach 回车上去
Zach, get back in the car.
请派辆急救车到橡树林大街860号!
I need an ambulance atabc860 oakwood avenue!
爸的车怎么发动了?
Why is dad's car on?
Zach 马上回车上去!
Get back in the car, zach!
快 快
Come on. Come on! Oh, come on.
别这样对我 Jeff! 不准这样!
Don't do this to me, jeff! Don't do this!
我很抱歉 我只是...
I'm sorry. I just...
不能再忍受那样的痛苦了
I couldn't take the pain anymore.
要不是我的表坏了abc就是小狼孩害你牺牲美容觉了
Either I need a new watch, or mowgliabcis cutting into your beauty sleep.
我整夜没睡 看财务报告abcRachel好极了
I was up all night looking at financeabcreports, and rachel is doing great.
谢谢关心
Thanks for asking.
证明比起无家可归的瘾君子abc你是更好的养母
Proving that you're a better fosterabcmom than a homeless drug addict.
部门预算这个星期要到期上报
Departmental budgets are due this week.
我需要延期
I'm gonna need an extension.
- 下个十年才有时间搞abc- Cameron已经帮你交了
- Got some time next decade.abc- Cameron already turned yours in.
她人真好
That's nice of her.
两个问题--abc为什么她要这样做?
Two questions--abcwhy did she?
而你为什么告诉我?
And why are you telling me?
同一个答案--现在你欠她人情了
Same answer-- nowabcyou owe her a favor.
我需要延期 下个--
I'm gonna need anabcextension.I got some time--
House 青少年及家庭服务署abc这周五会来家访
house, I've got a D.Y.F.S.abcHome visit on friday.
我也有性服务工作者来家访啊
And I've got aabcw-h-o-r-e visit on--
妈妈没空 你们到外面玩一会
mama's busy.You two are gonna haveabcto go play outside for a while.
32岁男性全身长期疼痛
32-year-old male withabcchronic pain all er.
你就让我帮这个忙?
This is the favor?
我还以为是跟生奶油abc压舌板有关的人情呢
I was expecting something involvingabcwhipped cream and tongue depressors.
三年内看了7位专家
He's seen seven differentabcspecialists over three years.
无确诊 痛苦也没有减轻
No diagnosis and no relief.
我已经被吸引住了
Oh, I am fascinated already.
这不是在治疗我自己嘛
It's like I'm treating myself.
他被治愈了 而我也上了abc人性的宝贵一课
He gets cured, and I get to learn a valuableabclesson about the milk of human kindness.
要是我觉得你还会学乖 就不会辞职了
If I thought you learnedabclessons, I never would've quit.
那浪费这个人情是因为?
So you're wasting a favor because?
我认为你可以治好他
I think you can help this guy.
他就是个骗止痛药的--
Drug-seeking patients--
这样的人不会放着一箱镇静剂去自杀
don't attempt suicide withabcmedicine cabinets full of narcotics.
听起来像纤维肌痛
Sounds like fibromyalgia.
听起来不像为House工作的人说的话
Sounds like you dot work for house.
没提供解释或治疗方法abc的诊断不算什么诊断
A diagnosis that provides neither an explanationabcnor a cure is by definition not a diagnosis.
美国风湿病学院不同意你这种说法
The american college ofabcrheumatology would disagree.
有具体的诊断标准
There are specific diagnostic criteria.
但无一符合这个病人
Which this guy doesn't meet.
按压他的痛处可以减轻痛楚 不会加重
Putting pressure on his painabchelps, doesn't make it worse.
他患有腹痛 剧烈头疼abc不时发作的肌肉抽筋
He's got abdominal pain, severeabcheadaches, muscle cramps that come and go.
他还想自行了断
And he tried to off himself.
明显是心理问题
He's obviously mentally ill.
痛感也许是心理上的
Pain's probably psychological.
想减轻痛楚可不是心理疾病的征兆
It is not a sign of mentalabcillness to want to be pain-free.
当你吸排气管废气去解决时就是了
it is if your solutionabcis sucking on a tailpipe.
理智的人不会自杀
Sane people don't attempt suicide.
从不?
Not ever?
那当你被绑在火刑柱上受刑abc有人递你把枪...
So if you were being burnt at theabcstake and someone handed you a gun...
我会用来射那个手拿火把的人
I'd shoot the guys with the torches.
过去三年没有一个医生找出他的毛病
Not one doctor this guy has seen in the past three yearsabchas been able to find a single thing wrong with him.
这意味着什么?
What does that tell you?
意味着他们都是白痴
It means they're idiots.
意味着我们得从头开始
It means we got toabcstart from the beginning.
做个疼痛评估 排除心病导致疼痛的可能abc去他家查查
We'll do a pain profile to rule outabcpsychosomatic pain, search the home.
你回家去  药得再配了 顺便带个面包圈
Go home. Get a refill... and a doughnut.
我去帮忙查他家
I'll help with the home.
选出最能表现你最近abc包括今天感觉的描述
"Choose a statement in each group "that best describesabchow you've been feeling lately, including today."
我没有抑郁
I'm not depressed.
我知道我的所为很蠢
I know what I did was stupid.
"我通常睡得很好" "我睡得不太好"abc"我睡得很不好"
"I usually sleep well. "I have some troubleabcwith sleep. I have a lot of trouble with sleep."
我睡得很不好
I have a lot of trouble.
时好时坏
It's up and down.
由于疼痛和药物作用abc他的睡眠很不稳定
Between the pain and the meds,abchis sleep pattern's pretty erratic.
"他很平和" "他比一般人紧张"abc"他神经兮兮的" "他很悲惨"
"He's a calm person. "He's more nervous thanabcmost people. He's so nervous, he's miserable."
肯定是平和
He's definitely calm.
有时候越疼越平和
Sometimes calmer theabcworse the pain gets.
我认为谈话和与他人互动abc反而会让他更糟
I think talking, interacting withabcother people actually makes it worse.
- 有意思abc- 为什么? 这意味着什么?
- Interesting.abc- Why? Does that mean something?
不 只是我们在另一个"病人"身上见过
No, it's just we've seenabcthat inther... patients.
"他能做家务"
"He can do chores around the house.
"有人帮助的情况下 他能做家务"abc"他不能做家务"
With help, he can do chores.abcHe can no longer do chores."
他常常帮忙的 他很壮
He helps all the time.abcHe's really strong.
他以前是打曲棍球的 打得很好
He used to play hockey.abcAnd he was really good too.
"我相信还有希望"
"I believe there's hope.
"希望事情好转对我来说比较辛苦"
"Hoping for things to getabcbetter is a struggle for me.
"大部分时间 我觉得希望很渺茫"
Most of the time, I feelabccompletely hopeless."
他常常笑的
He still laughs... all the time.
他以前就是个乐观的人 现在仍是
he was always optimistic. He still is.
只是...现在越来越难了
It's just... it's harder now.
我想...
I guess...
对我来说力量比希望更有用
I pray for strength more than hope.
除了一大堆止痛药之外什么都没有
There's nothing in there but aabcpharmacy's worth of pain meds.
跟他相比 House就像个教会科学家
This guy makes house lookabclike a christian scientist.
他还比House还遵循医嘱
He's also more compliant than house.
保留所有药品说明abc使用分药器避免把药弄混
Kept all the inserts, had daily pillabcdispensers to make sure he didn't mix them up.
一定要在车里窒息的话 这倒是辆好车
I gus if you're gonna go out in aabccar, this ain't a bad one to choose.
我要是自杀 肯定不会用这样的方法
If I ever did it, definitelyabcwouldn't be like that.
别担心 我没有计划自杀
Don't worry. I'm not making any plans.
我怎么会知道
I certainly wouldn't know.
自从我们接吻以后 你一直在逃避我
Ever since we kissed,you'veabcbeen avoiding me.
我没有 只是很忙
No, I haven't. Just been busy.
如果吸入过多金属抛光剂会使神经受损
Metal polish could cause nerveabcdamage if he inhaled enough of it.
从车的光泽来看 他肯定用得不少
Judging by the shine on thatabccar, he used a fair amount.
从他有家汽车美容店和这个来看abc他懂怎么保护自己
Judging by the fact that he owns a body shopabcand one of these, I'd say he knew not to inhale.
今晚有空吗? 我们一起吃晚饭吧
Busy tonight? We can get some dinner.
我看不行
I don't think so.
这么说亲热没问题abc吃饭却太亲密了?
So making out, okay.abcMeals, too intimate?
我也不想再跟你接吻了
I don't want to kiss you again either.
为什么? 因为我们是同事?
Why? Because we work together?
不 因为我喜欢你
No. Because I like you.
这解释得通啊
That makes a lot of sense.
我跟任何人在一起都解释不通
What doesn't make sense is meabcgetting involved with anyone.
我以为你早想通了呢
I thought you'd gotten past th.
所以才同意接受药物试验
That's why you agreed to the drug trial.
- 你不能放弃生活就因为--abc- 我没有放弃生活
- You can't give upon lifeabcbecause-- - I'm not giving upon life.
我只是放弃了你
I'm just giving upon you.
我终于觉得自己能把握住 我能接受了
I finally feel like I have aabcgrip on things. I can handle this.
不能接受的是把别人也拖下水
What I can't handle isabcdragging anyone else down with me.
这像鹌鹑吗?
Does this look like quail to you?
你认为他过去三年每天都吃有毒的食物?
you think he's had food poisoningabcevery day for the last three years?
野生鹌鹑可能有毒性 引起横纹肌溶解abc解释了疼痛
wild quail can be toxic, causeabcrhabdomyolysis, which would explain his pain,
也解释了肌酸激酶水平过高
as well as the elevated C.K.Levels.
他在车上吸的一氧化碳也一样
So would the carbon monoxide heabcsucked out of his car.
不是中毒反应 是身心反映
It's not a toxic reaction.abcIt's a psychosomatic reaction.
疼痛评估显示他太过担忧他的健康
The pain profile showed an excessiveabcconcern about his physical health,
难以入睡 不愿起床
difficulty sleeping,getting out of bed.
他不是因为沮丧才疼
He's not in pain because he's depressed.
是因为疼而沮丧
He's depressed because he's in pain.
就你吩咐我做的评估不是这么说的
Not according to theabcpain profile you ordered.
不是食物的问题
It's not a diet issue.
为了他和他家人abc我们应该给他抗抑郁剂
We should start him on antidepressantsabcfor his sake, as well as his family's.
我们又不是给他家人诊断
We're not diagnosing his family.
我们也不是在给你诊断
We're not diagnosing you either.
是横纹肌溶解症
It's rhabdo.
静脉注射 尿检 肌肉组织活检
Push I.V.Fluids, check hisabcurine, do a muscle biopsy.
什么肌肉? 他说全身都痛
What muscle? He says it hurts all over.
那就全身都活检
Then she'll biopsy all over.
你去哪?
Where are you going?
Cuddy能迟到 我就能早退
If cuddy can come inabclate,I can leave early.
我不在时有事 找Cameron去干
If you need anything while I'mabcgone, just ask cameron to do it.
他不吃鹌鹑 就不会痛了?
So if he just stops eatingabcquail, the painwill go away?
要是诊断没错的话 是可治愈的
If we're right,it'sabcdefinitely treatable.
我的手臂! 开始--
My arm! It's starting to--
他需要多点药
he needs more medicine.
血压下降 得头低足高放置
B.P.Is down. We need to getabchim in trendelenburg position.
Jeff 能听见吗?
Jeff, can you hear me?
他心跳要停止了
He's arresting.
我们需要急救推车!
we need a crash cart in here!
他连手机也没接
He's not answering his cell either.
肺通气灌注扫描显示有肺栓塞
V.Q.Scan showed a pulmonary embolism.
意味着他的疼痛不是心理上的
Means the pain's not psychosomatic.
也意味着不是横纹肌溶解症
it also means it's not rhabdomyolysis.
目前为止他的心肺是唯一不痛的地方
Up till now, his heart and lungs wereabcthe only places he didn't have pain.
意味着恶化了
Means it's getting worse.
想跛子接电话 铃声得多响几次
got to let the phone ring more thanabcfour times when you're calling a cripple.
长期疼痛和肺栓塞 说吧
Chronic pain and pulmonary embolism, go.
- 你怎么知道--abc- 过了12点还给我打电话
- How'd you know he had--abc- you called after midnight.
肯定是心脏问题
It's got to be a heart problem.
但是心脏问题跟横纹肌溶解症一致
But heart only would beabcconsistent with rhabdo,
这样13和Foreman就要乐得开花了
which means thirteen and foremanabcwould be singing in the rain,
这就是说肺肯定也有问题
which means it has to be lungs as well.
血液高凝会引起疼痛和肺栓塞
Hypercoagulable state couldabccause pain and a P.E.
你认为血块是由于血凝产生的 真有帮助
So you think the blood clot was causedabcby a clotting problem. That's helpful.
会是癌症综合症吗abc像Trousseau综合征?
What if it's a cancerabcsyndrome,like trousseau's?
解释了血块 多点疼痛abc缺乏明显的身体表征
Explains blood clots, multifocalabcpain, lack of obvious physical signs.
那为什么三年都没有人发现
And why he's gone threeabcyears without anyone seeing it.
验胸部 腹部和骨盆查肿瘤
Check his chest, abdomen,abcand pelvis for tumors.
为什么他说只有你们两会乐开花?
Why did he think only youabctwo would be singing in the rain?
骨窗正常
Bone windows are normal.
检查肺部是否有癌状肿块
Checking for cancerousabcmasses in the lungs.
你认识谁自杀了?
So, uh, who do youabcknow who committed suicide?
海明威 戈培尔(纳粹宣传部长)abc罗密欧与朱丽叶
Hemingway, goebbels, romeo and juliet.
你妈? 你爸?
Your mom? Dad?
就因为我说不管怎样都不会自杀abc意味着我全家自杀了?
Saying I wouldn't do it under any circumstancesabcmeans my whole family was suicidal?
不是 但是强烈反对某样东西abc意味着有历史--
No, but categorically insisting there areabcno circumstances means you've got baggage--
被出卖 被抛弃
personal betrayal, abandonment.
只因为自己生活像狄更斯小说...
Just because you grew up inabca charles dickens novel...
像我这样的人才不会自杀
well, it's peopleabclike me who don't do it.
生活开始糟透了 那就不能再糟了
When your life sucks from theabcbeginning, there's nowhere to go but up.
胸腔没事 肺部无肿瘤
Thorax is clear. No tumors in the lungs.
唯一的背叛者是躺在那儿的年度最佳父亲
The only betrayal comesabcfrom father of the year in there.
他的妻儿多么希望他活着
He has a wife,a kid-- peopleabcwho count on him to have a pulse.
好吧
Okay.
切换高分辨率检查腹部
Switching to high-resabccuts of the abdomen.
我父母住在皇后区 婚姻美满
My pents live very happily in queens.
他们从未试图 想过 或试图想过...abc怎么了?
They never attempted, thought about, orabcattempted to think about committ-- what?
这儿 横膜这儿
There, along his diaphragm.
不是癌症
That's not cancer.
不急 我这个礼拜已经洗过一次澡了abc我不想让人以为我是个精英主义者
No hurry. I already bathed once thisabcweek. I wouldn't want to look elitist.
写完评估之前什么也做不了
Can't do anything tillabcI write up an estimate.
行 写多少都行 这是我自费部分的支票
Fine. Pad it all you want.abcHere's a check for the deductible.
不准碰钢琴 走的时候锁门
Don't touch the piano andabclock up when you leave.
对不起 保险不包括这个
Sorry, deductible doesn't apply here.
我不是建筑师abc但我也知道主卧是房子的一部分
I'm no architect, but I'm pretty sureabcthe masterbedroom is part of the home,
- 所以说住宅保障...abc- 不包括过失
- which means the home warranty--abc- doesn't cover negligence.
水管顺着天花板 穿过墙 到了你的淋浴
This pipe goes through the ceiling,abcover that wall,and into your shower.
没破裂 是被拉开的
It didn't burst. It was pulled apart.
对 很明显我一起床abc就喜欢裸做几个引体向上
Yeah, 'cause I'm clearly a guy who likes to knockabcout a few naked pull-ups before I greet the day.
你在那边挂衣服么?
You hang laundry in there?
我要挂个水管工上去
I'm about to hang a plumber in there.
没有铁锈 没有腐蚀
Look,there's no rust.abcThere's no corrosion.
我不知道是怎么发生的 但是情况如此abc不在投保范围之内 所以...
I don't know how it happened, but I knowabcwhat happened,and it's not covered. So...
你准备好花2200块钱 找别人吧
whenever you're ready to spend theabc$2,200, give somebody else a call.
我保证 我只是握住你的手abc检察舞蹈样运动
I promise,I'm only holding yourabchand to check for choreiform movement.
绝对不含个人感情
I'm getting absolutely noabcintimacy from it.
我说了 跟你没关系
I told you, it hasabcnothing to do with you.
我知道 问题就在这儿
I know. That's the problem.
有80个理由我们不该约会abc但是你不该拒所有人于门外
There's 80 reasons we shouldn'tabcdate, but you can't shut everyone out.
你会需要帮助 支持的
You're gonna need help, support.
看看咱们那病人
Look at our patient.
32岁 还没咽气abc已经给老婆 儿子留下深深创伤
32 years old,not dead yet, and alreadyabche's traumatized his wife, his son--
他们肯定珍惜和他在一起的每一刻
and I'll bet they're cherishingabcevery traumatic minute he has left,
拿世界上最健康的人来 也不换
wouldn't trade him for theabchealthiest guy in the world.
那倒是 但他们绑定了跟他一起受苦abc每天怨气重重
True. And they're stuckabcsuffering with him, hating every day.
只是他们的痛苦没有解脱之日
Only their pain hasabcno prospect of relief.
打扰了?
This a bad time?
- 没abc- 是的
- No.abc- Yeah.
病人身上没有癌症迹象
No trace of cancer in the patient.
但是我们在他的肠子里发现水肿abc肠内血管中有气泡
But we did find edema in his intestines,abcair in the intestinal blood vessels,
House不接电话
and house won't answer his phone.
他的肠子肯定受到了损伤
His intestine must be damaged.
空气进入了身体
The air's leaking into his body.
要是肠系膜上动脉堵塞
if there's a blockage in theabcsuperior mesenteric artery,
血液就进不到肠部
it could be choking off bloodabcflow to his intestine.
全身性气栓能解释疼痛 偶发痉挛
Blockages all over his body would explainabchis pain, why the crampscomend go.
趁心肌梗死还没再次发作
Do an angioplasty on the superiorabcmesenteric and find the other blockages
赶快做肠系膜上动脉血管造影
before he has another cardiac arrest.
我来帮忙
I'll help.
没有一个有自杀倾向 浑身巨痛abc却又诊断不出毛病的病人真好
Good thing we don't have a suicidal patientabcwith a horrific,undiagnosed pain disorder.
确有此人  但是确诊了
We didtill we diagnosed it.
我们发现 肠水肿 血管中有气泡
We found intestinal edemaabcand air in the blood vessels.
疼痛是血管引起的
Pain was vascular.
如果是血管 会看到脉搏起伏的
If it was vascular,weabcwould've seen uneven pulses.
血压不稳 13和Kuntner在做血管造影
His blood pressure was uneven.abcThirteen and kutner are doing an angio.
他手指出血
He had hemorrhages in his fingers.
肠中有空气 肯定有来源
There's air in the intestine. Itabchas to have come from somewhere.
对 确实有
Yes... it does.
我们把导管从股沟插入到位
After we thread the catheterabcthrough his groin and into position,
血液流通就会恢复了
the blood willabcstart flowing freely again.
就不会再疼了么?
Will that take away the pain?
不会有任何效果 疼痛会完全消失
It will be completely ineffective,abcand the pain will completely go away.
取消血管造影
Cancel the angio.
他血管里有气泡abc如果不打通通往肠部的动脉...
He has air in his blood vessels. If weabcdon't open the artery to his intestines--
气泡能来自什么地方?
where can air come from?
可能来自小肠内腔的创口
Air can either come from a breachabcin the lumen in the small intestine,
偶尔 气泡来源于空气
or in rare instances,abcair can come from the air.
咬痕
Teeth marks.
我估计他是往吊针里吹气
I'm guessing from whenabche blew into his I.V.Tube.
气泡导致了肺栓塞和心肌梗死
Air bubb caused theabcP.E.And cardiac arrest.
你想完成在家里没成功的活啊
You tried to finish the jobabcthat you started at home.
Jeff... 为什么?
Jeff... why?
- 你说你决不会...abc- 我说谎了
- You said that you never--abc- I lied.
我想死
I want to die.
让我死吧
Please just let me die.
不
No.
他在高压氧舱里
he's in a hyperbaric chamber.
高压应该能把空气赶出来
A dose of high pressure ought toabcchase the air out of his blood.
有人看着他么
is anyone keeping anabceye on him, you know,
自杀监护就是为了自杀病人而设立的
because the whole idea of suicide watch wasabcspecifically created for suicidal patients.
你可能觉得这个名字只是巧合
I realize how you might've thoughtabcthe name was just a coincidence.
这房间有什么特别 非要在这上大课?
Are there any visuals in this roomabcthat are key to us learning our lesson?
因为电话...
'Cause the telephone--
你不给我好过 我就不给你好过
I'm inconveniencing youabcbecause you inconvenienced me.
- 你多久没洗澡了?abc- 这叫做男人体香...
- When was the last time you showered?abc- Scent of a man...
我知道你不喝醉了就体验不到
I realize you haven'tabcexperienced it sober.
抑郁疼痛病人的医生可是你啊...
If anyone should be able toabchandle a depressed pain patient...
- 他坚持他不再...abc- 很明显他说谎了
- he insisted he was noabclonger-- - apparently he lied.
真没想到还要我提醒你这点
Didn't think I'd have to remindabcyou of that remote possibility.
青少年及家庭服务署abc再有不到24小时就要来视察了
I have a D.Y.F.S.Inspectioninabcless than 24 hours,
- 如果你控制不了...abc- 非运动癫痫
- so if you can't control--abc- non-motor seizures.
对不起 我想的是病人 你说什么?
Sorry, I was thinking about theabcpatient. What were you saying?
- 继续abc- 疼痛是在腹部 肠部附近开始的
- go on.abc- The pain started in his abdomen near his intestine.
初始症状是关键
The first symptom has got to be key.
他做了很多次脑电图了abc哪个也比Cuddy的奶嘴干净
He's had multiple eegs, all of them cleaner andabcsqueakier than cuddy's rubber nipples.
糖原贮积病呢?abc比如肌磷酸化酶缺乏症
what about a glycogen storageabcdisease like mcardle's?
能解释疼痛
It explains the pain.
还有 肠内壁上有不少肌肉细胞
Plus, there's plenty of muscleabccells in the wall of the intestine.
14是对的
Fourteen is right.
去做一个缺血性前臂化验
Go run an ischemic forearm test.
出去的时候把垃圾拿出去
Take the garbage out on your way out.
你想男人给你倒垃圾 得先嫁给他
If you want a man to take yourabccrap, you have to marry him first.
或者雇了他
Or employ him.
好孩子
Good girl.
我还没准备好参加十项全能呢
I don't think I'm readyabcto run a decathlon yet.
如果我们提高你生活质量 就不错了
Ah, if we can get you managing yourabclife a bit better, that'll be plenty.
Hadley医生 我们准备好了
Dr. Hadley,whenever you're ready.
Janice 你好转了啊
Janice. You look better.
嗯 他们说我基底核指数好转了
Yeah, they said my basalabcganglian volume has improved.
我只知道2年来第一次
All I know is for theabcfirst time in two years,
我喝水不会撒得全身都是了
I can drink a cup of water withoutabcspilling it all over myself.
谢谢你让我回来参加研究
Thank you for gettingabcme back in the study.
我好几个礼拜没见过你了
I haven't even seen you in weeks.
我都不知道咱俩的时间又靠在一起了
I didn't even know our appointmentsabcwere back-to-back again.
没有 我今天早上才调的时间
Well, they weren't. Mineabcgot switched this morning.
我们要反复抽血
We're gonna take your blood repeatedly.
如果绑紧了让你胳膊更疼了abc那就是肌肉异常
If the increased strain makes your armabchurt more, you have a muscle abnormality.
如果是这个肌磷酸化酶缺乏症abc疼痛能消除么?
if you're right about this mcardle'sabcdisease, can you take away the pain?
用基因替换疗法 改变生活方式abc能减轻疼痛
With gene-replacement therapy,withabclifestyle changes, we can reduce it.
握紧球
Keep squeezing the ball.
- 他要多久...abc- 你和Zach出去吃点东西吧
- How long does he have to-- - maybeabcyou and zach should get something to eat.
- 亲爱的 别担心我们abc- 我不是
- Honey, don't worry about us.abc- I'm not.
请出去吧 我只能顾得了测试
Please get out of here. Theseabctests are all I can handle.
他们想帮你
They're trying to help you.
帮不了
They can't.
那帮他们呢? 别做个...
Then how about helpingabcthem,you know, by not being--
混蛋? 你不知道我有多痛苦
an ass? You have noabcidea what I'm going thrgh.
我知道比你想要的结果好
I know it's better than whatabcyou tried to go through.
还否认自己没经历过呢
Sure, no baggage at all.
现在更疼了么?
Where's the pain worst right now?
左臂 疼得更厉害了么?
Left arm. Does it hurt more?
疼得受不了
Couldn't.
乳酸水平正常 不是糖原
and lactate level is steady.abcIt's not any kind of glycogen.
噢 天哪! 腿开始疼了!
Oh, god! Pain jumped to my leg!
以前从未这样过
That's never happened before
胸部 腹部 有感觉么?
chest, your abdomen--youabcfeel anything there?
没有! 腿!
No! My leg!
感觉好像被锯断了一样
It feels like it's being sawed off.
- 真厉害abc- 什么?
- Nice.abc- What?
换了Janice的时间 让我看到天放晴abc就像电视里一样
Switching janice's appointment time so I couldabcsee the skies brighten like a lifetime tv movie.
- 你说什么...abc- 把改善最多的病人插到我眼前
- I don't know what you're-- - stking yourabcmost improved study participant in my face.
你就这么追我么?
Is that your way ofabcgetting into my pants?
时间不是我定的 就算是abc我也不会用做社交润滑剂
I don't make the schedule, and if I did,abcI wouldn't use itas a social lubricant.
而且 这是我头一回听说Janice好转了
And this is the first I'veabcheard of janice improving at all.
谢了
So, hey,thanks for the good news.
疼痛是从腹部开始的
Pain started in his abdomen.
从左手转移到左腿 跳过了整个躯干
Now it's hopped from his left thumb toabchis left leg, skipping the trunk entirely.
我要一个好律师的名字
I need the name of a good lawyer.
- 我们被告了?abc- 可能是 那是Cuddy的麻烦
- We're getting sued?abc- Probably. That's cuddy's problem.
游走的疼痛 说明是大脑而不是身体
hopping pain, means it's somethingabcin his brain,not his body.
大脑的两个区域分别控制两个疼痛点
Except the pain's in two places thatabcconnect to two separate regions of the brain,
说明你说话没经过大脑
which means you're not using yours.
别装了 你是犹太12支派的
Come on, you're fromabcone of the 12 tribes.
你认识一堆骗子
You know must know a ton of shysters.
你要什么样的律师?
What type of lawyer do you need?
下次地球统治附属委员会开会abc我会提出的
I'll bring it up at the next worldabcdomination subcommittee meeting.
我不是需要律师
Didn't say I needed a lawyer.
是需要律师的名字
I said I needed the name of a lawyer.
疼痛跳跃到同侧的另一肢体上
Pain hopped to anotherabclimb on the same side.
- 肯定是中央...abc- 排除不了边缘神经系统
- It's got to be central--abc- could still be peripheral.
如果椎间盘疾病的多个区域...
If multiple areasabcof disc disease--
和完全正常的核磁共振结果相符
were consistent with aabccompletely spotless mri.
你放火烧了那个病人abc是谁替医院辩护的?
Who represented the hospitalabcwhen you set that patient on fire?
Chris Carrick
Chris carrick.
Chris? 听着就不像个好律师
Chris? That doesn'tabcsound like a very good lawyer.
要是我们定不下来是大脑还是身体abc永远也确诊不了
If we can't even resolve body versusabcbrain, we're never gonna diagnose the guy.
律所的名字叫什么?
What was the name of the firm?
Caddell和Carrickabc我们又不能砍下他头 看还疼不疼了
Caddell and carrick. It's not like we canabcchop off his head to see if the pain goes away.
为什么不?
Why not?
要砍下人头
Need to cut off a guy's head.
要搞清楚疼痛是来自大脑还是身体
Got to figure out if his pain'sabccoming from his brain or his body.
脑干下一针利多卡因abc应该能一直麻到脚趾
A stiff shot of lidocaine below the brain stemabcshould numb him all the way down to his tippy toes.
我电话里跟你说"不行"还不够?
And hearing me say "no" overtheabcphone wasn't good enough?
你不给我好过 我就不给你好过
I'm inconveniencing you becauseabcyou inconvenienced me.
你知道领养官员今早要来
You know that foster-careabcofficial is coming in the morning.
要不是那样 也不用费老劲了
If they weren't,there'dabcbe no inconvenience.
不要逼我在孩子和...
Do not try and force me toabcchoose between my child--
我这是逼你工作!
I'm forcing you to do your job!
如果你不能一...
If you can't also--
行 你想把病人中央神经系统abc和身体其余部分分离
fine, you want to separate apatient's centralabcnervous system from the rest of his body.
如果疼痛还在 说明是大脑abc如果消失了...
If the pain stays,it's inabchis brain.If it vanishes--
那其他可能呢?
and what about optionsabcthree,four, and five?
他呼吸系统罢工 或者死于感染
His respiratory systemabcfreezes,or he dies of infection,
脑脊液到处乱喷
or he leaks cns fluidabclike a fire hydrant,
让他生不如死
which would make him wish he were dead?
擦去5号可能吧 他已经那样了
You need to scratch optionabcfive. He's already there.
你整天把客观挂在嘴边abc但是一碰到疼痛病人
You preach objectivity, but asabcsoon as a patient comes in in pain,
你只想探个究竟
all you want to do isabclook under the hood.
你不管是否有三分之一可能会杀死他
You don't care if there's aabcone-in-three chance you'll kill him.
要是我不确诊 他百分之百会自杀
If I don't diagnose him, there's aabcone-in-one chancehe'll kill himself.
我得走了
I got to go.
你觉得怎么对就怎么做吧
Do whatever it is you think is right.
Tammy 你说你会迟到一小会
Tammy, you said you wereabcgonna be a little late.
青少年及家庭服务署很快就到abc这个地方简直是鸡窝
D.Y.F.S.Is gonna be here in anabchour, and this place is a disaster.
算了
Never mind.
这会麻醉你胳膊以下的身体
This should numb everything fromabcyour shoulders down.
边缘性疼痛会消失
Any pain that'sabcperipheral should be gone.
- 你干什么啊?abc- 动动腿 继续
- What are you doing here?abc- just stretching my leg. Carry on.
今天很疼么?
Bad pain day today?
很快就不疼了abc别担心 他会让你感觉更好
About to get better. Don'tabcworry. He's making yours a double.
我记得吃药还管用的时候
I remember when the drugs stillabcmade things tolerable.
我还以为还有好日子可过
I still thought I had good days left.
得活下去才能知道
Turns out you have to live to find out.
你没有亲人 对吧?
You don't have a family, do you?
把他们留在氪星了(超人的故乡)
Left them all back on krypton.
你独身一人
You're alone.
所以能忍受疼痛
That's why you can handle your pain.
不用为了别人强颜欢笑
No need to put up a front, to beabcwhat anyone else wants you to be.
你最近不好受吧?
You're having more badabcdays lately,aren't you?
对
Yes.
那观望下未来吧
take a look at your future.
希望这次药物有用
Let's hope the drugs work this time.
我以为你没那么早来
I really wasn'tabcexpecting you till later.
有个约见取消了 就没依时间来见你
Had a cancellation, so Iabcthought I'd knock you off the docket.
抱歉这里一团糟 这周工作很辛苦
Well, I'm sorry this place is such a mess.abcIt's been a bit of a difficult work week.
屋子里有枪吗?
Any guns in the house?
没
Uh, no.
- 宠物? 除了蚂蚁?abc- 没
- Pets? Besides the ants?abc- No.
包很漂亮 这样扔尿布太贵
Nice bag. Pricey way toabcditch the diapers.
我平时不会 我太慌张了
That's not what I usually--abcum,I sort of panicked.
Calton先生 请让我解释
Mr. Carlton, if you'd justabcgive me a minute to explain.
- 我很满意abc- 真的?
- Everything looks fine.abc- Really?
Cuddy医生 你收入丰厚abc个性坚定 工作稳定
Dr. Cuddy, you've got sufficient income, a highabcdegree of personal and professional stability,
你很在意这次回访abc所以对屋子乱感到羞愧
and you care enough to be embarrassedabcby what a mess this place is.
你可是我所探访寄养妈妈中的佼佼者
Believe me, that puts you head and shouldersabcabove most of the foster moms I visit.
如果明年你还没有收养她的话abc那时再见了
See you next year, if youabchaven't adopted her by then.
我的腿 好些了
My legs... they're different. Better.
- 一点都不疼?abc- 不 没那么疼
- No pain at all?abc- No, but less.
四成疼 也许五成
Four out of ten, maybe five.
不可能
Can't be.
如果是大脑造成疼痛abc那并没有消除
If whatever is causing the pain isabcin your brain, it's still a ten.
但末梢疼痛应该为零
Periphery is zero.
确实 有些痛消失了 有些还在
It is. Some of the painabcis gone, but not all of it.
这说明什么?
What does this mean?
也许Taub是对的
maybe taub was right.
是心理因素造成了身体症状
It's psychosomatic after all.
谁是House?
Which one of you is house?
壮黑哥们
The big black guy.
Chris Carrick
Chris carrick.
下次你冒我名写恐吓信abc就不是赔钱这么简单了
Next time you use my name in a threateningabce-mail, it won't be just a bill.
我会起诉你
It'll be a lawsuit.
能怪我么?abc上次陌生人找我 冲我就是一枪
Can you blame me? The last timeabcthat happened,the guy shot me.
会不会脊髓麻醉触发了安慰剂效应?
What if the spinal block triggeredabcsome sort of placebo effect?
这家伙吃的是最好的鸦片剂
Guy's taken the finestabcopiates blue cross can buy.
药片怎么没触发安慰剂效应?
How come they didn'tabctrigger a placebo effect?
怎么了?
What happened?
他突然叫起来 帮帮他
he just started screaming, do something!
千万别是他爸爸一样的病
Please, god, do not letabcit be what his father has.
他是假装的
I think he's faking.
你怎么这么说
How dare you? Whatabcmakes you think--
- House 孩子是剧痛abc- 他去哪儿?
- house, the kid's in excruciating--abc- where is he going?
- 在哪儿?abc- 什么?
- Where is it?abc- Where's what?
蠢儿子吸引医护工的注意力abc一心求死的老爸吞下一瓶异丙基
His idiot son distracted the orderlies so that daddyabcdeath wish here could down a bottle of isopropyl.
给他做透析 不然半小时后 他就死了
Get him on dialysis, or inabchalf an hour,he'll be a corpse.
- 你弄痛我了abc- 记住这份痛
- You're hurting me.abc- Remember the feeling.
下次想帮老爹时 要演得逼真些
Maybe next time you want to helpabcpops, you'll do a better acting job.
你帮不了他
You can't help him.
Zach 为什么要这么做?
Zach, why did you do this?
因为他不再是老爸了
Because he's not dad anymore.
他只想快点结束
He just wants it to be over with.
就让他死吧
Please. Please,just--just let him die.
Fabry症能引起中枢和末梢疼痛
fabry disease might be able toabccause central and peripheral pain.
他没有血管角质瘤
No angiokeratomata.
梅毒引起的刺割样疼痛
Lightning pain from syphilis.
梅毒检测是阴性
All the syph tests were negative.
- 你们怎么不说话了abc- 因为没辙了
- Why aren't you guys still talking?abc- Because we ran out of ideas.
什么都解释不了
nothing explains this.
总有个答案
Something has to.
除非 没有病能解释
Unless... nothing does.
- 你也认为--abc- 我想的有些巧妙
- So now you think-- - mine's aabcmore interesting version of nothing.
曾经有某种疾病
It used to be something.
什么都找不到abc是因为最初造成疼痛的伤害早已痊愈
We can't find anything because whatever injuryabccaused the original pain healed a long time ago.
留下的是药物
The only thing left is the drugs.
是镇痛剂造成了疼痛
Opioid induced pain.
疼痛和镇痛物的机理都是改变脑部化学
Pain and the drugs that treat painabcwork by changing brain chemistry,
到了某种程度abc痛觉受体会把镇痛药解读成剧痛
sometimes to the point where painabcreceptors read painkillers as killer pain.
让他断药
Take him off the drugs.
治不好他 就折磨他?
We can't cure him,soabcwe're gonna torture him?
折磨能治好他
Torture is his cure.
他的身体最终会自我调整
Eventually his body willabcrecalibrate itself.
要是你没推断错的话
Assuming you're right.
我想不出有其他可能
Yes. I find it confusing toabcassume otherwise.
让你戒了维柯丁怎么样?
How would you like toabcstop taking vicodin?
幸好我不是病人
Good thing I'm not the patient.
门开着
It's open.
- 谢谢abc- 太大了么?
- Thank you.abc- Is it too big?
她长大 会爱上的abc放那儿好啦
She'll grow into it.abcYou can put it there.
家庭视察推后了?
I take it the homeabcinspection was pushed back.
我通过了
I passed.
值得高兴啊
You do realize that's a good thing?
这里乱透了
This place was a disaster.
我不得不把脏尿布藏到手提包里
I had to stash a dirtyabcdiaper in my briefcase.
那就换个手袋
So you buy another briefcase.
我让House自治
I let house supervise himself.
就好比给12岁孩子酒柜和车子的钥匙
That's like handing a 12-year-old theabckeys to the liquor cabinet and the car.
你通过视察了
You passed the inspection.
病人活着 车子还在停车位
The patient lived. The carabcis still in the driveway.
那下次呢?abc当保姆请假 House又想把人锯成两半
And the next time my nanny gets sickabcwhen house wants to saw someone in half?
我有强调你通过了么?
Did I mention you passed the inspection?
符合了他们宽松的标准abc但过不了自己这关
By their meager standard.abcI failed by mine.
为什么女人总这样?
Why do women always do that?
失败?
Fail?
对事业 对孩子abc都树立没人能达到的苛刻标准
Create ridiculous standards that no humanabccould meet, with your careers,with your kids.
你应该向男人学学
You got to be more like us men.
偷懒? 撇清责任?
Be lazy? Blame others?
求助!
Get help!
做到你这个职位的男人在工作上有个副手abc两个助手 在家还有一个老婆 两个保姆
Most men in your position have a deputy and twoabcassistants at work, and a wife and two nannies at home.
你既不是超人 也不是圣人
You're not superwoman. Don't be a martyr.
我们给你注射纳洛酮abc会阻断痛觉受体对镇痛剂的反应
We'll be injecting you with naloxone, which willabcknock the opioids out of your pain receptors.
如果我们猜对了 身体会在几小时内调整abc大部分疼痛会消失
If we're right, your system will recalibrate withinabca few hours, and most of the pain will be gone.
几小时? 我需要药物
Hours? I need those drugs.
如果是引起你疼痛的根源 就不行
Not if they're causing your pain.
- 把我弄晕 用镇静剂abc- 那也是要服药的
- Then knock me out,sedate meabcwhile you-- - that'll take drugs too.
得把药物清除出你的系统
We need to clearabceverything out of your system.
求求你 什么都行
Please,I'll try anything else.
这就是我们要停止的
That's what we're trying to stop.
不是你父母
So it's not your parents.
- 那是你妻子 亲近的人abc- 一个同事
- Then it's your wife, someoneabcyou were close-- - a colleague.
我们同是医师
We were residents together.
我该多关心些 阻止事态发展
I should've done more to stop it.
他有救世主情结
He had the mother of all god complexes.
忙着医治别人 忽略了自己
So busy treating everyone'sabcproblems, he was blind to his own.
给自己注射了一瓶胰岛素
Helped himself to a vial of insulin.
能活下来是奇迹
It's a miracle he survived.
他的朋友和家庭差点离他而去
His friends and family almost didn't.
他很自私
He was a selfish ass.
很快就好了
It'll be over soon.
真是疯了
This is lunacy.
为了一个猜想就这样折磨人
You're torturing this guy on a hunch.
我们只有这一个猜想
It's the only hunch we've got.
我要真像折磨他 我就操纵一项药物试验abc来让他和你睡
If I really wanted to torture him, I'd manipulate aabcclinical trial in the hopes that he'd sleep with you.
你在暗示 我让13加入药物试验abc是为了私人目的?
Are you suggesting I got thirteen inabcthat trial because of some personal--
我认为你是出于惯常的弥赛亚情结abc让她加入的
I think you got her in becauseabcof your usual messiah complex.
我猜你是因为"我要做爱"情结abc而刻意调整了预约时间表
I think you messed with the appointment scheduleabcbecause of your "I like to have sex"complex.
我查过记录
I checked the logs.
你把进步最大的病人恰好安排在她之前
You moved your mostabcpromising patient right before her.
虚无的希望能当春药用
False hope being quite the aphrodisiac.
如果试验有成效abc怎么能说是虚无的希望呢
How's it false if theabctrials are showing results?
如果这么有效 你又何必调整预约表
Well, if it were that promising, youabcwouldn't have to change the schedule.
管它呢 希望春天永驻
But, hey... hope springs eternal.
烹饪事故?
This was a cooking accident?
第一次做樱桃布丁
First time making cherries jubilee.
好大的火势
Awfully big fire.
食谱里的一些配方下次可不能用了
If you ask me, some of theabcportions in that recipe were off.
希望保险能理赔
Sure hope it happens toabcbe covered under, say,
依据第3款 第2.2分款abc第1段 意外火灾
section three, subsection 2.2,paragraphabcone, accidental fire damage,
你得更换所有的水管abc修理松垂的管道
in which case you'd have to replace theabcentire waterline to fix the sagging pipe.
我看是的
I guess so.
可你隔壁邻居以后就没热水用了
Hate to have your next-doorabcneighbors end up with no hot water.
幸好火苗没窜到外面
Lucky the fire escapedabcyour pipes entirely.
没用
It's not working.
知道 我让他用回止痛片了
I know. I started him backabcon the pain meds...
- 你怎么还不走abc- 我儿子是对的
- which means you can leave.abc- My son was right.
- 我一直努力不让他...
I tried for so long toabcprotect him from...
我才是最自私的
but I'm the one who's been selfish.
他没法活下去了
This is no way for him to live.
除非我们找到答案 这是唯一的方法
Until we get an answer,abcit's the only way.
没有答案
There is no answer.
- 总是有答案的abc- 那是什么?
- There's always an answer.abc- Then what is it?
他入院4天
He's been here four days.
3次试图自杀 你没有答案
Three suicide attempts.abcYou don't have an answer.
当我看到你...
When I saw you...
看到拐杖 我想"感谢上帝"
when I saw the cane,abcI thought, "thank god."
这位医生能理解
The doctor will understand.
我无法理解的
Because i sure as hell don't.
我丈夫认为该结束了
My husband thinks it's over.
请诚实地告诉我 你会愿意如此活下去
So look me in the eye, tellabcme you'd want to live like that.
让他稳定下来
Then stabilize him.
让他能支持走完回家的路
Get him in decent enoughabcshape for the drive home.
然后他终于能...
So he can finally...
好
okay.
肯定还有我们能做的abc不能让病人这样离开
There's got to be something we can do.abcWe can't just let the patient leave.
不是我们放病人走 是House
we didn't. House did.
他意识到无法可想了
because he realized there'sabcnothing he could do.
总有我们能做的 有法子可试
there's always something we canabcdo, something else we can try.
你疯了 知道不?
You're insane. You know that, right?
因为我有原则?
Because I have principles?
因为你贿赂我 索偿申请造假花的钱abc比整个修理费还多
Because you paid more to bribe me to lie onabcyour claim than the entire cost of the repair.
付钱我不在乎 只要让过去九年里abc在我保险金上揩油的人也付钱
I don't care if I pay, as long as the pple whoabcpocketed my premiums for the last nine years also pay.
我没弄破水管
I didn't break the pipe.
要是你想坚定立场 我无所谓
Whatever. If you want to stickabcit to the man, that's fine by me.
- 你开心了?abc- 不 但我做得对
- You happy?abc- Nope,but I'm right.
出去时锁门
Lock upon your way out.
别碰钢琴
And don't touch the piano.
睾丸 让你想到什么?
Testicles. What doabcthey make you think of?
性病 睾丸激素问题 火岛的夏天
Stds, testosterone issues,abcthat summer on fire island.
很接近了
oh, so close.
正确的答案是癫痫症
The correct answer is epilepsy.
癫痫症不会导致长期疼痛
Epilepsy doesn't cause chronic pain.
如果扩散到大脑的感觉区域abc搅乱痛觉神经 就会的
It does if it spreads to the sensory regionabcof the brain, then rewires the pain neurons.
会在脑电图中显示
Would've shown upon an eeg.
如果癫痫发作的区域在大脑深处abc在脑电图中就看不到
Not if the seizures are in a place you can'tabcsee on an eeg, a place too deep in the brain,
控制某些肌肉 例如支持...
like the area that controls theabcmuscles supporting the...
睾丸
testicles.
觉得好像是睾丸被踢了一脚 是么?
Feels like you got kicked inabcthe nads, doesn't it?
腹痛 开始哪里疼?
The abdominal pain, how it all started.
不是肚子 位置更低 是么?
It wasn't the stomach.abcIt was lower, right?
到处都疼
It's everywhere.
一开始的疼痛呢?
But when it first started.
开始是肚子绞痛
It started in the stomach--cramps.
是胀气 还是侵入式的疼痛...
Like bad gas, or a permeating pain...
就像肾被从阴囊里扯出来
like your kidneys are being pulledabcout through your scrotum.
干嘛问?
Why?
因为癫痫是能治好的
Because epilepsy is treatable.
看来我们把拿火把的人打死了
like we shot the guys with the torches.
是啊 付着钱 只为了在这儿闲逛
Yeah. Pays to hang around.
那个差点自杀 有救世主情结的傻蛋
That selfish ass with the god complex whoabcalmost made the stupidest decision of his life--
不是同事 而是你吧?
wasn't your colleague,wasabcit? It was you.
不
No.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
你来得早
You're here early.
我感觉好多了
I'm feeling better.
- 怎么了?abc- 有些漏 没关系 我去去就来
- What's wrong?abc- I.V.'S leaking a little. It's no big deal. I'll be right back.
Foreman
Foreman.
你今晚有安排吗?
You busy tonight?
没
No.
RitaabcHadley医生输液袋上的针头没插到底
Rita, the spike on dr. Hadley's I.V.abcBag wasn't pushed in all the way.
- 我不想剂量有误差abc- 对不起 一定注意
- I don't want any dosing errors.abc- Sorry. It won't happen again.
- 很刺鼻 是么?abc- 什么?
- It stinks, doesn't it?abc- What?
药物 更换输液袋时能闻到 很恶心
The medication. When we switch out theabcbags,you can smell it. It's disgusting.
我没闻到
I didn't smell anything.
那她用的肯定是安慰剂
Oh, she must be on the placebo, then.
你帮House做部门预算 是想让他欠着你
You offered to do house's budgetabcbecause you wanted him to owe you,
想他接这个病例 为什么?
wanted him to take that case.Why?
我觉得能帮到Houseabc看到有人情况比他更糟
I thought it would help house--abcseeing someone worse off than him,
治好一个希望比他更渺茫的人abc能鼓舞他
possibly curing a guy whoabchas even less to look forward to.
有事问你
Can I ask yousomething?
你做我的工作怎么样?
How would you like my job?